A Guide to the John K. Martin Records, 1777-1907
Library of Virginia
- Pension Files, 1777-1883 and n.d., 10.62 cubic feet. (Boxes 1-24)
  - Mexican War, 1846-1881 and n.d., 0.45 cubic feet. (Boxes 20-21)
    - Mexican War - Leckie-Patton (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - McAvoy, Michael, 1879 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - McDevett, Francis, 1852-1853 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Parkinson, John H., 1857 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Patman, Watson, 1846-1858 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Patton, David G., 1854-1856 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Patton, James, 1852-1854 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Mexican War - Seddon-Wright (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Seddon, John, 1850-1854 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Shackelford, A. J., 1879 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Shoemaker, George R., 1858 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Starke, Henry, 1847-1857 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Starke, Henry, 1857-1866 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Thornton, Charles, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Via, David G., 1853-1854 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Wright, John, 1853-1855 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Native American Wars, 1850-1858, 0.23 cubic feet. (Box 21)
    These are pension files, 1850-1858, for claimants with military service during the Black Hawk War, Seminole Wars, and Sioux Uprising.
    - Black Hawk War - Derr-Johnson (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Crawford, Andrew, 1854 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Derr, Martin, 1852-1857 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Jennett, William, 1856-1857 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Johnson, Robert, 1857 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Seminole Wars - Deacon-Hartz (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Deacon, George A., 1852 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Ellett, James M., 1858 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Furze, James D., 1851-1856 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Gennett, Armistead, 1850 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Graham, Robert, 1856-1857 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Hartz, John, 1854 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Seminole Wars - Miller-Williams (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Miller, George, 1851 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Parkinson, James S., 1850-1857 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Pemberton, George K., 1851-1852 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Peter, John, 1857 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Pinhorn, George W., 1854-1855 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Poarch, Wingfield, 1857-1858 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Smith, Daniel J., 1857 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Williams, Joseph, 1851-1852 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Sioux Uprising - William H. Bailey 1856-1857 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Civil War, 1853-1882 and n.d., 0.23 cubic feet. (Box 21)
    These are pension files, for claimants with military service during the American Civil War.
    - Civil War - Burkhardt-Dippner (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Burkhardt, John, 1870-1872 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Burton, H. W., 1861 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Burton, R. C., 1861 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Clark, George L., 1867 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Cook, George W., 1861 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Crouch, Hasell W., 1862 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Dippner, Claus, 1864-1881 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Civil War - Gray-Kimbrough (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Gray, William H., 1867 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Hall, [_], 1866 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Harkness, John T., 1866 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Hoffman, E. L., 1875-1881 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Houston, James W., 1862 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Hull, Benjamin F., 1853-1861 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Jackson, James Henry, 1862 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Jones, J. W., 1862 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Key, Robert, 1863-1864 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Kimbrough, Thomas M., 1861 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Civil War - Limb-O'Dey (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Limb, Frederick, 1863-1877 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Lotsey, Thomas, 1877 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Martin, Theodore R., 1861-1865 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - O'Dey, Dennis, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Civil War - Pitts-Taylor, Curtis (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Pitts, A. I., 1863 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Rhodes, G. T., 1862 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Riddick, Thomas S., 1864-1865 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Self, Job, 1864 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Sullavoe, Samuel, 1873 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Taylor, Bradley, 1880 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Taylor, Curtis, 1867-1878 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Civil War - Taylor, Thomas-Via (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Taylor, Thomas A., 1861 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Trainer, [_], 1861 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Tysinger, W. E., 1861 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Vandegriff, J. W., 1862 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Via, Thomas D., 1879 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified War, 0.90 cubic feet. (Boxes 22-23)
    These are pension files for claimants of military service during unidentified wars.
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by claimants' surname with individual items within each folder arranged chronologically.
    - Unidentified War - Aires-Ayres (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Aires, John, 1879 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Aldridge, Bennett, 1867 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Alley, Alfred, 1858 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Alvis, Charles, 1878 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Andrews, S. A., 1851-1852 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Armistead, Thomas, 1857 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Atkesson, Amos, 1854 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Ayres, Samuel, 1858 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified War - Bailey-Bernard (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Bailey, John W., 1854-1856 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Bailey, William H., 1854 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Ballance, Edmund, 1853 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Barrow, Thomas, 1855 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Bass, Thomas W., 1856 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Beale, W. H., 1878 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Bennett, Eli, 1855-1856 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Bennett, Henry, 1872 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Bernard, P. D., 1852 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified War - Berry-Bowling (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Berry, George, 1875 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Blankenship, Q. M., 1878 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Booker, George E., 1856 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Bougue, Jonathan, 1856 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Bowden, Lemuel J., 1854 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Bowles, [_], 1852-1854 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Bowling, James, 1863 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified War - Branch-Carter (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Branch, [_], n.d. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Bray, Winter, 1856 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Brown, Christopher, 1852 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Brown, Tucker, 1852 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Buckner, William, 1854 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Burchett, William H., 1850-1854 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Burkhardt, John, 1875 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Burton, [_], n.d. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Carr, John, 1842-1856 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Carrington, John Lewis, 1878 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Carter, Henry, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified War - Caulfield-Coffee (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Caulfield, William, 1851 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Christian, James, 1881 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Christian, [_], 1881-1882 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Clarks, [_], 1855 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Clark, Charles S., 1880 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Clingman, T. L., 1858 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Cocke, Harrison C., 1857 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Coffee, [_], 1881 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified War - Coleman-Croxton (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Coleman, Elisha, 1853-1857 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Coleman, Ferdinand G., 1855 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Coleman, William D., 1856 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Collins, William, 1855 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Courtney, James, 1860 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Cox, Bartlett, 1853 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Craddock, John, 1856 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Croxton, Thomas, 1859 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified War - Crump-Dunham (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Crump, F. W. P., 1853 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Crump,Richard, 1857-1858 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Crutchley, Benjamin, 1853 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Cuffey, Charles, 1858 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Curry, Jonathan G., 1854-1855 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Curry, [_], 1856 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Deakins, Philip, 1853 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Deveney, Aaron, 1851 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Donohoo, William J., 1854-1855 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Durham, John, 1852 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified War - Durkin-Evans (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Durkin, Patrick, 1852 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Eanes, [_], 1856-1857 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Ellett, James M., 1858 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Elliott, Nelson, 1856 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Elliott, [_], n.d. (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Ellis, Absalom, 1853 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Espy, Samuel, 1851 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Estes, Aaron, 1835 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Eustace, J. H., 1850 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Evans, John, 1851 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified War - Ferguson-Frayson (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Ferguson, Theodorick, 1855-1858 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Flippin, James E., 1856 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Foggry, John, 1857 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Folks, Joseph, 1858-1859 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Forse, [_], 1878 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Fountain, [_], 1854 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Fox, Braden E., 1879 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Fraysen, Christopher C., 1857 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified War - Gill-Haiden (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Gill, John, 1854-1858 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Gillespie, D. L., 1855 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Goodman, [_], 1858 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Gray, [_], 1852 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Green, A. M., 1881 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Green, George, 1855-1857 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Hagen, Bernard, 1855-1856 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Haiden, Jesse, 1877-1879 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified War - Hamilton-Hartz (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Hamilton, James, 1854, 1866 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Hamilton, Tillman, 1856 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Hanbury, Matthew T., 1828, 1854 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Harlan, [_], 1856 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Harper, George W., 1857-1858 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Harris, Peter, 1855 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Hartz, John, 1837 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified War - Hatcher-Hobson, Benjamin (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Hatcher, [_], 1878 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Hehn, Adam, 1857 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Henderson, Pleasant, 1854 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Henley, Peyton F., 1857 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Henson, Suilly, 1854 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Higgins, Prosser, 1863 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Hill, Robert, 1851-1879 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Hitchcock, Hartwell, 1855 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Hobgood, John R., 1856 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Hobson, Benjamin, 1855 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified War - Hobson, John-Jacobs (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Hobson, John, 1852 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Hockaday, Richard, 1853 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Holman, William M., 1861 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Howard, [_], 1877 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Howell, Charles, 1869 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Hubbard, Richardson, 1855 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Hughes, Isaac, 1854 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Jacobs, William, 1882 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified War - Jennett-Kimbrough (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Jennett, William, 1854-1855 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Jerrold, William, 1857 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Johnson, Henry, 1875 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Jones, [_], 1856 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Jones, John P., 1853 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Jones, William, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Jones, [_], 1853 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Kay, William, 1854 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Keesee, Charles, 1818 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Kenneday, William M., 1855 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Kimbrough William I., 1858 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified War - King-Lipscomb (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - King, Henry, 1877 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - King, John, 1852 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - King, [_], 1853 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Kozster, I. W., 1852-1854 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Lacy, Shadrick, 1853 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Lambert, Thomas, 1856 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Lark, David C., 1873 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Lavender, William, 1852 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Leckie, John, 1858 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Lee, [_], 1854 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Lipscomb, David, 1856 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified War - Lomax-Marker (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Lomax, Albert, 1858 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Lombard, George, 1879 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Lovin, [_], 1854 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Lucas, [_], 1854-1855 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - McAlexander, Alexander, 1851 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - McArthur, Moses, 1857 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Mann, James H., 1853 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Mann, [_], 1857 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Marker, Frederick, 1855 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified War - Marshall-Miles (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - MArshall, John, 1870 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Marshall, John D., 1854 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Martin, Humphrey H., 1856 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Martin, Joseph, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Matthews, [_], 1853 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Matthews, George, 1856 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Mauck, Henry W., 1860 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Maxey, [_], 1856 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Miles, Drewry, 1851 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified War - Miller-Moore (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Miller, [_], 1875 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Miller, [_], n.d. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Miller, Thomas, 1856 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Mills, Zachariah, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Mitchell, A. C., 1855 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Montague, [_], 1855 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Montgomery, William, 1855-1857 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Moody, Henry, 1858 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Moore, John W., 1860-1861 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Moore, [_], 1872 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Moore, [_], 1882 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified War - Nash-O'Connor (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Nash, Reuben, 1878 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Neilson, Hall, 1872 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Nelson, [_], 1847 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Nelson, John, 1852 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Noel, Richard, 1879 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Nutter, Christopher, 1853-1854 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - O'Connor, John, 1860 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified War - O'Neal-Perry (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - O'Neal, John, 1851 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - O'Neal, William, 1852 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Overton, Samuel, 1812-1828 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Parr, [_], 1879 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Parr, Hullum, 1878-1879 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Parrish, Matthew, 1855 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Patterson, Thomas, 1881 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Patton, David, 1854-1857 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Pau, [_], 1878 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Payne, Tarlton F., 1854 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Penick, Nathaniel, 1856 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Pepp, Nicholas S. R., 1857 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Perry, Reuben, 1858 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified War - Peskin-Reagan (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Peskin, John, 1879 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Peters, [_], 1854 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Phaup, Benjamin, 1858 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Phaup, [_], 1857 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Pipkin, Isaac, 1876 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Pitt, Richard W., 1855 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Poarch, Winfield, 1858 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Read, George B., 1857 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Reagan, Daniel, 1848 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified War - Robinson-Shook (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Robinson, John, 1852 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Rogers, John, 1878 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Salmon, G. B., 1855 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Scott, [_], 1881 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Seal, Theophilus, 1854 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Shackleford, Warner, 1857 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Sharp, George, 1874 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Sheets, [_], 1878 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Sheppard, Anderson, 1855-1857 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Shook, John H., 1852 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified War - Sibley-Stuart (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Sibley, [_], 1856 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Simmons, William C., 1852 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Simpkins, [_], 1855 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Singleton, Anthony, 1825 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Slaughter, John, 1852 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Slayton, Robert, 1852 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Slussman, John, 1854 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Smith, I. N., 1855 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Smith, Israel, 1875 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Spears, [_], 1856 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Stewart, Joseph, 1878 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Stryker, Henry S., 1880 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Sullivan, [_], 1877 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Sullivan, Daniel V., 1878 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Stuart, Willis, 1857-1858 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified War - Sutherland-Trent (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Sutherland, Alexander, 1852 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Sweeney, Andrew, 1853 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Tansil, [_], 1879 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Tarrant, [_], 1856 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Terry, Champness, 1858 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Thompson, Henry C., 1848-1853 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Thompson, James, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Thompson, Roger, 1856 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Thurman, Hezekiah, 1853 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Tibbs, Demarchur Jackson, 1856-1857 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Tinwell, Francis, 1856 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Towles, Henry, 1852 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Townes, Armistead, 1858 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Trent, William, 1859 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified War - Tyree-Williams, John (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Tyree, Isham, 1850 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Tyree, John M., 1854 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Underwood, Samuel, 1855 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Vandervall, Daniel, 1827, 1866 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Via, D. G., 1854 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Watkins, Stephen, 1854-1855 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Wetheram, James, 1852 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Whealey, [_], 1857 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - White, N., 1851 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Williams, Isaac W., 1857 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Williams, John, 1860-1861 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified War - Williams-Yates (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Williams, Joseph, 1852 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Williams, Willamson, 1853 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Williams, William W., 1852 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Wood, Henry, 1857 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Woody, Samuel, 1853-1855 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Wollard, [_], 1856 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Worthen, James, 1856 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Yates, John, 1857 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Registers of Action on Claims, 1848-1882, 0.26 cubic feet. (Boxes 24)
    Consists of registers of action and notes on pension claims. There are four volumes dated 1848-1852, 1850-1858, 1853-1857, and 1878-1882. Notes pension claimant's name and action or notes on claimant taken by John K. Martin.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Register of claims, 1848-1852 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Register of notes on claims (formerly Book B), 1850-1858 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Register of notes on claims, 1853-1857 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Register of action on claims, 1878-1882 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Business Correspondence, 1.58 cubic feet. (Boxes 25-28)
  Business correspondence, 1832-1883 and n.d., principally consisting of letters concerning his general business as a land agent and exchanged with attorneys, judges, politicians, and Federal and state officials. There is also correspondence with specific land agents concerning claims, land bounty warrants, and other business related to military claimants. Also contains correspondence with United States mail agents.
  Arranged in three subseries: A. General, B. Land Agents, C. United States Mail Agents.
  - General, 1832-1883 and n.d., 1.1 cubic feet. (Boxes 25-27)
    Correspondence, 1832-1883 and n.d., concerning John K. Martin's general business as a land agent. The correspondence is principally exchanged between Martin and clerks, attorneys, judges, politicians, and Federal and state officials and concerns the delivery, purchase and sale of bounty land warrants and scrip.
    - 1832-1842 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - 1844-1849 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - 1850 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - 1851 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - January-June 1852 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - July-December 1852 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - January-April 1853 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - May-December 1853 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - 1854 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - 1855 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - 1856 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - 1857 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - 1858 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - 1858, 1863 (Box 34a, Folder 4)
    - 1859 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - 1860 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - 1861-1862 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - 1863-1865 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - 1866 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - 1867 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - 1868-1869 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - 1870 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - 1871-1872 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - 1873-1874 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - 1875 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - 1876 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - 1877 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - January-July 1878 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - August-December 1878 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - 1879 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - 1880 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - 1881 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - 1882-1883 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - n.d. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Land agents, 1850-1881 and n.d., 0.45 cubic feet. (Boxes 27-28)
    Correspondence, 1850-1881 and n.d., exchanged between Martin and specific land agents. These were the agents with whom Martin corresponded most frequently during his many years as a land agent. Concerns the delivery, purchase and sale of bounty land warrants and scrip. There are also circulars sent to Martin from the United States Pension Office.
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by agent's surname and within each folder the correspondence is arranged chronologically.
    - Black, L. C., 1876-1877 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Braddock, John, 1876-1877 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Ford, Hezekiah, 1851-1858, 1878 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Hall, Jeremiah, 1854-1858, 1876 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Henry, P. M., 1853-1881 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Lewis, Warner, 1851-1854 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1851-1879 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Neely, John T., 1850-1858 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Niles, Samuel V., 1855-1871 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Niles, Samuel V., 1873-1876 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Niles, Samuel V., 1877-1881 and n.d. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Pension Office circulars, 1844-1881 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - United States Mail agents, 1840-1861, 0.11 cubic feet. (Box 28)
    Correspondence, 1840-1861, principally exchanged between Martin and United States Mail agents during the period when Martin was a mail agent. Concerns his routine duties as well as his termination as mail agent following the election of Millard Fillmore, a Whig, as President.
    - 1840-1848 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - 1849-1861 (Box 28, Folder 6)
- Personal Correspondence, 1826-1907 and n.d., 0.45 cubic feet. (Box 29)
  Personal correspondence, 1826-1907 and n.d., of John K. Martin and Michael Howell, Martin's father in-law, principally concerning Martin and Howell family matters and land transactions. There is also correspondence exchanged between members of the Palmeter family of Richmond, Virginia, and New York. The link of the Palmeter family to this collection is uncertain.
  Arranged in three subseries: A. John K. Martin, B. Michael Howell, C. Palmeter Family.
  - John K. Martin, 1847-1907, 0.22 cubic feet. (Box 29)